There is a subtle difference between assessing your data and exploring your data.
هناك اختلاف دقيق بين تقييم بياناتكم واستكشاف بياناتكم.
Assessing is part of the data wrangling process,
التقييم هو جزء من عملية المعالجة الشاملة للبيانات،
while exploring is part of Exploratory Data Analysis or EDA.
في حين أن الاستكشاف هو جزء من تحليل البيانات الاستكشافي أو EDA.
Data wrangling is about gathering the right pieces of data,
تتعلق المعالجة الشاملة للبيانات بجمع البيانات الصحيحة،
assessing your data's quality and structure,
وتقييم جودة البيانات وبنيتها،
then modifying your data to make it clean.
ثم تعديل بياناتكم لجعلها نظيفة.
But the assessments you make and convert to cleaning operations,
لكن عمليات التقييم التي تقومون بها وتحولونها إلى عمليات تنظيف،
won't make your analysis,
لن تقوم بتحليلكم المراد،
VIS, or model better though.
أو VIS، أو إنتاج نموذجكم بشكل أفضل.
The goal is just to make them work.
الهدف فقط جعلها تعمل.
EDA is about exploring your data to later augment it,
يتعلق تحليل EDA باستكشاف بياناتكم لتعزيزها فيما بعد،
to maximize the potential of your analyses, visualizations and models.
لزيادة إمكانات تحليلاتكم ومرئياتكم ونماذجكم.
When exploring, simple visualizations are
عند الاستكشاف، غالبًا ما يتم استخدام مرئيات بسيطة
often used to summarize your data's main characteristics.
لتلخيص الخصائص الرئيسية لبياناتكم.
From there, you can do things like remove outliers and
ومن هنا، يمكنكم القيام بأشياء مثل إزالة القيم الشاذة
create new and more descriptive features from existing data,
وإنشاء ميزات وصفية جديدة أكثر وضوحًا من البيانات الموجودة،
also known as feature engineering.
والتي تُعرف أيضًا باسم هندسة الميزات.
In practice, wrangling and EDA can occur together,
عمليًا، يمكن القيام بالمعالجة الشاملة وتحليل EDA معًا،
but we're going to separate them for teaching purposes.
ولكن سنفصلهما لأغراض التعليم.